<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<examples>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ "Hello, World!" Program</title>
        <desc>Source code to display a sentence in C++ programming...</desc>
        <relative_path>print-sentence.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Print Number Entered by User</title>
        <desc>In this example, you'll learn to print the number entered by a user using C++ cout
            statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>read-print-integer.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Add Two Numbers</title>
        <desc>Source code to add two numbers using three variables and two variables in C++
            programming..
        </desc>
        <relative_path>add-numbers.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find Quotient and Remainder</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to find the quotient and remainder of a given dividend
            and divisor.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>quotient-remainder.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find Size of int, float, double and char in Your System</title>
        <desc>Source code to find the size of int, float, char etc in your system in C++ programming
            using sizeof operator..
        </desc>
        <relative_path>sizeof-operator.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Swap Two Numbers</title>
        <desc>This example contains two different techniques to swap numbers in C programming. The
            first program uses temporary variable to swap numbers, whereas the second program
            doesn't use temporary variables.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>swapping.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Whether Number is Even or Odd</title>
        <desc>In this example, if...else statement is used to check whether a number entered by the
            user is even or odd.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>even-odd.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Whether a character is Vowel or Consonant.</title>
        <desc>Source code to check whether a character entered by user is a vowel alphabet or not in
            C++ programming..
        </desc>
        <relative_path>vowel-consonant.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find Largest Number Among Three Numbers</title>
        <desc>In this example, you'll learn to find the largest number among three numbers using if,
            if else and nested if else statements.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>largest-number-among-three.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find All Roots of a Quadratic Equation</title>
        <desc>Source code to find all roots of a quadratic equation in C++ programming...</desc>
        <relative_path>quadratic-roots.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Calculate Sum of Natural Numbers</title>
        <desc>In this example, you'll learn to calculate the sum of natural numbers.</desc>
        <relative_path>sum-natural-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Leap Year</title>
        <desc>This program checks whether an year (integer) entered by the user is a leap year or
            not.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>leap-year.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find Factorial</title>
        <desc>The factorial of a positive integer n is equal to 1*2*3*...n. You will learn to
            calculate the factorial of a number using for loop in this example.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>factorial.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Generate Multiplication Table</title>
        <desc>Example to generate the multiplication table of a number (entered by the user) using
            for loop.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>multiplication-table.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Display Fibonacci Series</title>
        <desc>Source code to display Fibonacci series up to n number of terms and up to certain
            number entered by user in C++ programming..
        </desc>
        <relative_path>fibonacci-series.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find GCD</title>
        <desc>Examples on different ways to calculate GCD of two integers (for both positive and
            negative integers) using loops and decision making statements.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>hcf-gcd.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find LCM</title>
        <desc>Examples on different ways to calculate the LCM (Lowest Common Multiple) of two
            integers using loops and decision making statements.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>lcm.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Reverse a Number</title>
        <desc>Source code to reverse an positive integer entered by user in C++ Programming...
        </desc>
        <relative_path>reverse-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Calculate Power of a Number</title>
        <desc></desc>
        <relative_path>power-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>Increment ++ and Decrement -- Operator Overloading in C++ Programming</title>
        <desc>In this example, you'll learn to overload increment ++ and decrement -- operators in
            C++.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>increment-decrement-operator-overloading.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Subtract Complex Number Using Operator Overloading</title>
        <desc>This page contains the tutorial on overloading of binary operator in C++
            programming....
        </desc>
        <relative_path>binary-operator-overloading.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find ASCII Value of a Character</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to find ASCII value of a character in C++.</desc>
        <relative_path>ASCII-value-character.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Multiply two Numbers</title>
        <desc>In this program, user is asked to enter two numbers (floating point numbers). Then,
            the product of those two numbers is stored in a variable and displayed on the screen.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>product-numbers.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Whether a Number is Palindrome or Not</title>
        <desc>This program reverses an integer (entered by the user) using while loop. Then, if
            statement is used to check whether the reversed number is equal to the original number
            or not.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>palindrome-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Whether a Number is Prime or Not</title>
        <desc>Example to check whether an integer (entered by the user) is a prime number or not
            using for loop and if...else statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>prime-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Display Prime Numbers Between Two Intervals</title>
        <desc>Example to print all prime numbers between two numbers (entered by the user) in C++
            Programming. This problem is solved using nested for loop and if...else statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>prime-number-intervals.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Armstrong Number</title>
        <desc>Example to check whether an integer (entered by the user) is an Armstrong number or
            not using while loop and if...else statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>check-armstrong-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Display Armstrong Number Between Two Intervals</title>
        <desc>Example to find all Armstrong numbers between two integers (entered by the user) using
            loops and if...else statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>armstrong-number-interval.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Display Factors of a Number</title>
        <desc>Example to find all factors of an integer (entered by the user) using for loop and if
            statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>factors-number.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Programs To Create Pyramid and Pattern</title>
        <desc>Examples to print half pyramid, pyramid, inverted pyramid, Pascal's Triangle and
            Floyd's triangle in C++ Programming using control statements.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>pyramid-pattern.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Make a Simple Calculator to Add, Subtract, Multiply or Divide Using
            switch...case
        </title>
        <desc>Example to create a simple calculator to add, subtract, multiply and divide using
            switch and break statement.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>calculator-switch-case.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Display Prime Numbers Between Two Intervals Using Functions</title>
        <desc>Example to print all prime numbers between two numbers (entered by the user) by making
            a user-defined function.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>prime-interval-function.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Prime Number By Creating a Function</title>
        <desc>You will learn to check whether a number entered by the user is prime or not by
            passing it to a user-defined function.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>prime-function.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Check Whether a Number can be Express as Sum of Two Prime Numbers
        </title>
        <desc>Example to check if an integer (entered by the user) can be expressed as the sum of
            two prime numbers of all possible combinations with the use of functions.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>sum-prime-numbers.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ program to Find Sum of Natural Numbers using Recursion</title>
        <desc>Example to find the sum of natural numbers by using a recursive function.</desc>
        <relative_path>natural-number-sum-recursion.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ program to Calculate Factorial of a Number Using Recursion</title>
        <desc>Example to find factorial of a non-negative integer (entered by the user) using
            recursion.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>factorial-recursion.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find G.C.D Using Recursion</title>
        <desc>Example to find the GCD of two positive integers (entered by the user) using recursion
            in C programming.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>hcf-recursion.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Convert Binary Number to Decimal and vice-versa</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to convert binary number to decimal, and decimal
            number to binary manually by creating user-defined functions.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>binary-decimal-convert.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Convert Octal Number to Decimal and vice-versa</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to convert octal number to decimal and decimal number
            to octal manually by creating a user-defined function.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>octal-decimal-convert.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Convert Binary Number to Octal and vice-versa</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to convert binary number to octal, and octal number to
            binary manually by creating a user-defined function.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>octal-binary-convert.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ program to Reverse a Sentence Using Recursion</title>
        <desc>This program takes a sentence from user and reverses that sentence using recursion.
            This program does not use string to reverse the sentence or store the sentence.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>reverse-sentence-recursion.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Calculate Power Using Recursion</title>
        <desc>This program calculates the power of a number using recursion where base and exponent
            is entered by the user.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>power-recursion.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Calculate Average of Numbers Using Arrays</title>
        <desc>This program takes n number of element from user (where, n is specified by user),
            stores data in an array and calculates the average of those numbers.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>average-arrays.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find Largest Element of an Array</title>
        <desc>This program takes n number of element from user (where, n is specified by user) and
            stores data in an array. Then, this program displays the largest element of that array
            using loops.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>array-largest-element.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Calculate Standard Deviation</title>
        <desc>This program calculates the standard deviation of 10 data using arrays.</desc>
        <relative_path>standard-deviation.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Add Two Matrix Using Multi-dimensional Arrays</title>
        <desc>This program takes two matrices of order r*c and stores it in two-dimensional array.
            Then, the program adds these two matrices and displays it on the screen.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>add-matrix.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Multiply Two Matrix Using Multi-dimensional Arrays</title>
        <desc>This program takes two matrices of order r1*c1 and r2*c2 respectively. Then, the
            program multiplies these two matrices (if possible) and displays it on the screen.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>matrix-multiplication.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find Transpose of a Matrix</title>
        <desc>This program takes a matrix of order r*c from the user and computes the transpose of
            the matrix.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>matrix-transpose.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Multiply two Matrices by Passing Matrix to Function</title>
        <desc>In this example, you'll learn to multiply two matrices and display it using user
            defined function.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>matrix-multiplication-function.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Access Elements of an Array Using Pointer</title>
        <desc>This program declares the array of five element and the elements of that array are
            accessed using pointer.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>access-array-pointer.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Swap Numbers in Cyclic Order Using Call by Reference</title>
        <desc>This program takes three integers from the user and swaps them in cyclic order using
            pointers.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>swapping-cyclic-order.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find the Frequency of Characters in a String</title>
        <desc>In this example, frequency of occurrence of a character is checked for both (String
            object and C-style string).
        </desc>
        <relative_path>frequency-character.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find the Number of Vowels, Consonants, Digits and White Spaces in a
            String
        </title>
        <desc></desc>
        <relative_path>vowel-consonant-frequency-string.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Remove all Characters in a String Except Alphabets.</title>
        <desc>You will learn to remove all characters from a string (string object and C-style
            string) in this example.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>remove-characters-string.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Find the Length of a String</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to compute the length (size) of a string (both string
            objects and C-style strings).
        </desc>
        <relative_path>string-length.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Concatenate Two Strings</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to concatenate (join) two strings (both string objects
            and C-style strings).
        </desc>
        <relative_path>concatenate-string.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Copy Strings</title>
        <desc>In this example, you will learn to copy strings (both string objects and C-style
            strings).
        </desc>
        <relative_path>string-copy.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Sort Elements in Lexicographical Order (Dictionary Order)</title>
        <desc>This program sorts the 10 strings (entered by the user) in lexicographical order
            (dictionary order).
        </desc>
        <relative_path>lexicographical-order.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Store Information of a Student in a Structure</title>
        <desc>This program stores the information (name, roll and marks entered by the user) of a
            student in a structure and displays it on the screen.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>structure-store-information.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Add Two Distances (in inch-feet) System Using Structures</title>
        <desc>This program takes two distances (in inch-feet system), adds them and displays the
            result on the screen.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>inch-feet-structure.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Add Complex Numbers by Passing Structure to a Function</title>
        <desc>This program takes two complex numbers as structures and adds them with the use of
            functions.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>complex-number-add.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Calculate Difference Between Two Time Period</title>
        <desc></desc>
        <relative_path>time-structure.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
    <example>
        <language>cpp</language>
        <title>C++ Program to Store and Display Information Using Structure</title>
        <desc>This program stores the information (name, roll and marks) of 10 students using
            structures.
        </desc>
        <relative_path>information-structure-array.cpp</relative_path>
    </example>
</examples>